We all have milestones in life that we remember so vividly.
لدينا جميعا مواقف بالحياة نتذكرها بكل وضوح.
The first one for me was when I was entering kindergarten.
أول موقف بالنسبة لي، كان عند دخولي روضة الأطفال.
My big brother was in school, and by golly, it was my time.
كان أخي الأكبر في المدرسة، ويالفرحتي! قد حان وقتي.
And I went trottin' down that hallway.
ذهبت بكل سرور نحو المدخل.
I was so excited, I almost wet myself.
كنت متحمسة للغاية، كدت أن أبلل نفسي.
And I go to the door,
واتجهت نحو الباب،
and there was the teacher with a warm welcome,
وهناك كانت تقف المعلمة ترحب بي ترحيبًا حارًا،
and she took me into the classroom,
واصطحبتني إلى الفصل،
showed me my little cubbyhole --
وأرتني خزانتي المكعبة الصغيرة --
we all remember those little cubbyholes, don't we --
نتذكر كلنا تلك الخزانات، أليس كذلك ؟
and we put our stuff in there.
ونضع فيها أغراضنا.
And then she said, "Go over to the circle
بعدها قالت، "اذهبي لتلك المجموعة
and play with the kids until class starts."
والعبي مع الأطفال حتى تبدأ الحصة."
So I went over there and plopped down like I owned the place,
فذهبت إلى هناك أتمايل كأني أملك المكان،
and I'm playing,
وكنت ألعب،
and all of a sudden, the boy next to me,
إذ فجأة يقوم فتى بجانبي،
he was wearing a white shirt with blue shorts.
كان يرتدي قميصًا أبيض وبنطالًا أزرق.
I remember it like it was yesterday.
أتذكره كأنه حدث بالأمس.
Suddenly he stopped playing and he said,
توقف فجأة عن اللعب وقال:
"Why are you so short?"
لمَ أنتِ قصيرة هكذا؟"
And I just kept playing. I didn't think he was talking to me.
واستمريت باللعب. لم أظن أنه كان يتحدث إليّ.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And in a louder voice, he said,
وقال بصوت أعلى،
"Hey, why are you so short?"
"ياهذه! لم أنت قصيرة هكذا؟"
So I looked up and I said,
لذا نظرت إليه وقلت:
"What are you talking about? Let's just play. We're happy.
"عن ماذا تتحدث؟ دعنا نلعب فقط. نحن سعداء.
I've been waiting for this."
لقد كنت بانتظار هذا."
And so we played, and about a minute later,
ولعبنا هكذا، بعدها بدقيقة،
the girl next to him, in a white shirt and a pink skirt,
الفتاة التي بجواره، ترتدي قميصًا أبيض وتنورة وردية
stood up, put her hands on her hips,
وقفت واضعةً يدها على خصرها،
and said, "Yeah, why do you look so different?"
وقالت: "نعم، لم تبدين مختلفة هكذا؟"
And I went, "What are you talking about?
واستمريت بالقول: "عن ماذا تتحدثون؟"
I don't look different. I'm not short. Again, let's just play."
أنا لا أبدو مختلفة. أنا لست قصيرة. مرة أخرى، دعونا نلعب فحسب."
About this time, I looked all around the circle I was in,
في هذا الوقت، نظرت حولي في المجموعة التي كنت بها،
and all the kids had stopped playing and they were all looking at me.
وتوقف جميع الأطفال عن اللعب وظلوا يحدقون بي.
And I'm thinking --
وظللت أفكر --
in today's language, it would be "OMG" or "WTF."
في لغة اليوم الدارجة، قد تكون "يا إلهي" أو"ما هذا الهراء."
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
What just happened?
ماذا حدث للتو؟
So all the confidence that I went in with that morning
لذا تلاشت الثقة التي كنت أجول بها ذاك الصباح
was withering away as the morning went on
مع مرور الوقت في هذا الصباح
and the questions kept coming.
وظل السؤال يتردد.
And at the end of the morning, before I went home,
وفي نهاية الصباح وقبل عودتي للمنزل،
the teacher had us in a circle,
جمعتنا المعلمة في دائرة،
and I actually found myself outside of the circle.
ووجدت نفسي حقيقةً خارج الدائرة.
I couldn't look at anybody.
لم أستطع النظر لأي أحد.
I could not understand what just happened.
لم أستوعب الذي حدث للتو.
And over the next few years,
وعلى مدار السنوات التالية،
I hated to go out in public.
لم أحب الخروج أمام العامة.
I felt every stare, every giggle,
كنت أشعر بكل نظرة، بكل همسة،
every pointed finger,
كل إصبع يشير إلىّ،
not the finger,
ليست الأيدي،
but every pointed finger,
بل حتى مجرد إشارة الإصبع،
and I hated it.
وكرهت ذلك.
I would hide behind my parents' legs like nobody could see me.
كنت أختبئ خلف والداي حتى لا يراني أي أحد.
And as a child,
وكوني طفلة،
you can't understand another child's curiosity,
لم أستطع تفهم فضول الطفل الآخر.
nor an adult's ignorance.
ولا تفهم تجاهل الكبار.
It became very apparent to me that the real world was not built
كان الأمر واضحًا لي أن هذا العالم لم يخلق
for someone of my size, both literally or figuratively.
لشخص في مثل حجمي، بوجه حرفي أو مجازي.
And so I have no anonymity, as you can probably tell,
لذا لم يعد لدي أي هوية، كما ربما تعرفون،
and while you can see my size,
وبينما بإمكانكم رؤية حجمي،
we all go through many challenges through our lifetime.
نمر جميعًا بتحديات كثيرة على مدى حياتنا.
And some you can see, like mine.
بعضهم تستطيعون رؤيتهم مثلي.
Most you can't.
وأغلب البعض الآخر لاترونهم.
You can't tell if someone's dealing with a mental illness,
لا تعرف إن كان أحد يعاني من مرض عقلي،
or they're struggling with their gender identity,
أو إن كانوا يكافحون من أجل هويتهم الجنسية،
they're caring for an aging parent,
يعتنون بوالد مسن،
they're having financial difficulty.
أو لديهم صعوبة مادية.
You can't see that kind of stuff.
لا تستطيعون رؤية هذه الأشياء.
So while you can see
لذا بينما ترون
one of my challenges is my size,
أحد تحدياتي التي تواجهني مع حجمي،
seeing does not mean you understand
رؤيتكم بأعينكم لاتعني أنكم تفهمون
what it's truly to be me on a daily basis, or what I go through.
حقيقة أن أكون هكذا يوميًا أو الذي أمر به.
And so I'm here to debunk a myth.
أنا هنا لكشف الزيف عن أسطورة.
I do not believe you can walk in someone else's shoes,
أؤمن حقا أنكم تقدرون على وضع أنفسكم مكان الآخرين،
and because of that, we must adopt a new way of giving of ourselves.
وبسبب هذا، علينا اعتماد طريقة جديدة لتقدير أنفسنا.
Simply stated, I will never know what it's like to be you
ببساطة، لن أعلم أبدًا ما يعنيه أن أكون مكانك
and you will never know what it's like to be me.
وأنت أيضا لن تعرف معنى أن تكون مكاني.
I cannot face your fears or chase your dreams,
لا أستطيع مواجهة مخاوفك أو مطاردة أحلامك،
and you can't do that for me,
وأنت لا تستطيع فعل هذا بدلا مني،
but we can be supportive of each other.
لكن نستطيع أن ندعم بعضنا البعض.
Instead of trying to walk in each other's shoes,
بدلا من محاولة وضع أنفسنا مكان الآخرين،
we must adopt a new way of giving of ourselves.
علينا إيجاد طريقة جديدة لتقدير أنفسنا.
I learned at an early age
تعلمت في وقت مبكر
that I did have to do some things different than most people,
أنني تعين علي أن أقوم بأمور مختلفة عن غالبية الناس،
but I also learned there were things I was on equal footing with,
لكني تعلمت أيضا أن هناك أشياء كنت فيها على قدم المساواة معهم،
and one of those was the classroom.
وأحد هذه الأمور كان الفصل.
Heh, heh, heh. I was equal.
كنت متساوية.
As a matter of fact, I excelled in the classroom.
في حقيقة الأمر، كنت متفوقة في الدراسة.
This was vitally important, I discovered as I grew older
كان هذا مهم للغاية، اكتشفت بينما أكبُر
and realized I wasn't going to be able to do a physical job.
وأدركت أنني لن أستطيع القيام بالمهمة الحركية.
I needed an education.
كنت بحاجة للتعليم.
So I went on and got a university degree,
لذلك سعيت جاهدة وحصلت على الدرجة الجامعية،
but I felt to be one step ahead of everyone for employment,
لكن شعرت أني أريد أن أسبق الجميع بخطوة من أجل الوظيفة،
I needed to have an advanced university degree,
احتجت الحصول على درجة جامعية أعلى،
so I went ahead and got that.
سعيت لذلك وحصلت على ما أريد.
Now I'm ready for my interview.
أنا الآن مستعدة للمقابلة الوظيفية.
Remember your first interview? What am I going to wear?
تتذكرون أول مقابلة عمل؟ ماذا سأرتدي؟
What questions?
ما نوعية الأسئلة؟
And don't forget that firm handshake.
ولا تنسى المصافحة الجادة.
I was right there with you.
كنت هناك بجانبك.
So 24 hours before my interview,
لذا في الـ٢٤ ساعة قبل مقابلتي الشخصية،
a friend of mine who I've known all my life
صديقة لي أعرفها طيلة حياتي
called and said, "Michele, the building you're going in has steps."
اتصلت بي وقالت "ميشيل، المبنى الذي ستذهبين إليه به سلالم"
And she knew I couldn't climb steps.
كانت تعلم بأنيً لا أستطيع صعود السلم.
So suddenly, my focus changed.
لذا فجأة تغير محور تركيزي.
In my shoes, I was worried about how am I going to get there?
في وضعي، ساورني القلق حول كيفية صعودي لذاك السلم؟
So I went early and found a loading dock and got in and had a great interview.
ذهبت مبكرة واستخدمت حامل أغراض وقمت بمقابلة مذهلة.
They had no idea what I went through for the day and that's OK.
ليست لديهم أدني فكرة عن ماذا فعلت لأصل إليهم وهذا لا بأس به.
You're probably thinking my greatest challenge that day was the interview,
قد تعتقدون أصعب تحدي واجهته ذاك اليوم هو المقابلة الشخصية،
or getting in the building.
أو صعودي للدور العلوي.
In reality, my biggest challenge that day
في الحقيقة، أكبر تحدي ذاك اليوم
was getting through the loading dock without getting run over.
كان عدم انزلاقي من على حامل الأغراض.
I am very vulnerable in certain situations:
أنا أعتبر ضعيفة خاصة في بعض المواقف:
airports, hallways, parking lots,
المطارات والممرات ومواقف السيارات،
loading docks.
حاملات الأغراض.
And so I have to be very careful.
وعلي أن أكون حذرة للغاية.
I have to anticipate and be flexible
علي أن أكون منتبهة وأتمتع بالمرونة
and move as quickly as I can sometimes.
و أسير بأقصى سرعة ممكنة أحيانًا.
So I got the job,
حصلت على الوظيفة،
and in my current role I travel quite a bit.
وفي وظيفتي الحالية أسافر كثيرًا.
And travel is a challenge for all of us these days.
والسفر أصبح صعبًا هذه الأيام.
And so you probably get to the airport, run through security, get to the gate.
وربما تصلون المطار، وتمرون على نقاط التفتيش وتصلون إلى البوابة.
Did I get my aisle seat or my window seat? Did I get my upgrade?
هل حصلتُ على مقعد بجوار الممر أم بجوار النافذة؟ هل حصلت على ترقيتي؟
Me, first of all, I don't run through anything.
أنا، بادئ ذي بدء، لا أمر على أي شيء.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And I especially don't run through the TSA
وخاصةً لا أمر على إدارة أمن المواصلات
because I get to experience the personal patdown.
لأنه على أن أخضع لتفتيش ذاتي.
I won't comment on that.
لن أعلق على هذا.
And then I make my way to the gate,
وبعدها أذهب في طريقي إلى البوابة،
and with my gift of gab that my parents said I was born with,
وبموهبتي في الإلقاء التي أخبرني والداي أني ولدت بها،
I talk to the gate agent, and then I say, "By the way, my scooter weighs this much,
أتكلم مع حارس البوابة وأقول، "بالمناسبة، تزن دراجتي كذا،
I have a dry cell battery,
لدي بطارية جافة،
and I can drive it down to the door of the plane."
وأستطيع قيادتها نحو باب الطائرة."
Also, the day before, I had called the city where I'm traveling to
أيضًا، قبلها بيوم، اتصلت بالمدينة التي سأسافر إليها
to find out where I could rent a scooter in case mine gets broken on the way.
لأعرف أين يمكنني أن أستأجر دراجة في حال تعطلت دراجتي في الطريق.
So in my shoes, it's a little bit different.
لذا في وضعي، الأمر مختلف بعض الشيء.
When I get onto the plane,
عندما أدخل الطائرة،
I use my gift of gab to ask the lady to put my bag up, and they graciously do.
أستخدم موهبتي في الحديث لأطلب من سيدة أن ترفع لي حقيبتي وتفعل ذلك بلطف.
I try not to eat or drink on a plane
أحاول ألا آكل أو أشرب في الطائرة
because I don't want to have to get up and walk on the plane,
لكي لا أضطر إلى النهوض والمشي في الطائرة،
but nature has its own schedule,
لكن الطبيعة لها حكمها الخاص،
and not long ago, it knocked and I answered.
ومن وقت ليس ببعيد، دقت الطبيعة ورددت عليها.
So I walked up to the front of the plane
لذا سرت نحو مقدمة الطائرة
and gabbed with the flight attendant,
واستخدمت موهبتي في الإلقاء مع مضيفة الرحلة،
and said, "Can you watch the door? I can't reach the lock."
وقلت، "هل تستطيعي حراسة الباب؟ لا أستطيع أن أصل لقفل الباب."
So I'm in there doing my business, and the door flies open.
لذا أنا هناك أقوم بأموري، وانفتح الباب.
And there's a gentleman there
وكان يوجد هناك رجل
with a look of horror on his face.
على وجهه نظرة رعب.
I'm sure I had the same look.
بالتأكيد لدي نفس رد الفعل.
As I came out, I noticed that he was sitting right across from me,
وعند خروجي لاحظت أنه كان يجلس في الناحية المقابلة لي مباشرةً،
and he's in total, complete embarrassment.
وكان كليًا يشعر بالحرج.
So I walk up to him and I quietly go,
لذا اتجهت نحوه وقلت بهدوء،
"Are you going to remember this as much as I am?"
"هل ستتذكر هذا بقدْري؟"
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And he goes, "I think so."
وقال: "أعتقد هذا."
Now, while he's probably not talking about it publicly, I am.
ربما هو لم يتحدث عنه علنًا، لكني أفعل الآن.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
But we talked for the rest of the flight,
لكنا تحدثنا بقية الرحلة،
and we got to know each other, our families, sports, work,
وتعرفنا على بعضنا، عائلاتنا، الرياضة، العمل،
and when we landed, he said,
وعندما هبطت الطائرة، قال،
"Michele, I noticed someone put your bag up.
"لاحظت يا ميشيل أن هناك من رفع حقيبتك.
Can I get that for you?"
هل أستطيع أن أجلبها لكِ؟"
And I said, "Of course, thank you."
وقلت، "بالطبع، شكرا لك."
And we wished each other well,
وودعنا بعضنا،
and the most important thing that day
وأهم ما حدث ذاك اليوم
was that he was not going to leave with that embarrassment,
أنه لم يمضِ بهذا الحرج،
that experience of embarrassment.
إحساس الحرج هذا.
He won't forget it, and neither will I,
هو لن ينسى الأمر ولا أنا أيضًا،
but I think he will remember more
لكن أعتقد أنه سيتذكر المزيد
our chat and our different perspectives.
من حوارنا ووجهات نظرنا المختلفة.
When you travel internationally,
عندما تسافر دول أخرى،
it can be even more challenging in certain ways.
يزداد الأمر صعوبة بطرق معينة.
A few years ago, I was in Zanzibar,
منذ بضع سنوات، كنت في (زانزيبار)،
and I come wheeling in,
وذهبت على كرسيي المتحرك،
and think about that.
وأفكر بشأن هذا.
Short, white, blond woman in a chair.
امرأة قصيرة وبيضاء وشقراء تتحرك باستخدام كرسي.
That doesn't probably happen every day.
ربما هذا لا يحدث كل يوم.
So I go up, and with my gift of gab, I start to talk to the agent.
لذا قمت واستخدمت موهبتي وبدأت الحديث مع الحارس.
So friendly, and I ask about their culture and so forth,
بأسلوب ودي جدًا وسألت عن ثقافتهم وهكذا،
and I notice there wasn't a jet bridge.
ولاحظت أنه لم يكن هناك جسر للعبور نحو الطائرة.
So I had to kind of say,
لذا كان علي أن أقول،
"Not only do you have to lift my chair,
"ليس علي فقط أن أرفع كرسيّي،
I could use some help getting up the steps."
أحتاج لبعض المساعدة في صعود السلم."
So we got to spend about an hour together while we waited for the flight,
لذا قضينا ساعة معًا أثناء انتظار الطائرة،
and it was the most magnificent hour.
وكانت أكثر ساعة مهمة.
Our perspective changed for both of us that day.
تغيرت وجهة نظر كلينا ذاك اليوم.
And once I got on the flight,
وبمجرد صعودي على الطائرة،
he patted me on the back and wished me well,
ربّت على كتفي وودعني،
and I thanked him so much.
وقدمت له خالص شكري.
And again, I think he's going to remember that experience more
ومرة ثانية، أعتقد أنه سيتذكر هذا الكلام
than when I first came in, and there was a bit of hesitation.
أكثر من أول مرة ظهرت فيها، وكان هناك قليل من التردد.
And as you notice, I get a lot of help.
وكما تلاحظون، تلقيت كثيرا من المساعدة.
I would not be where I am today
لم أكن لأصبح هنا اليوم
if it was not for my family, my friends, my colleagues
إذا لم تساعدني أسرتي وأصدقائي وزملائي
and the many strangers
والعديد من الغرباء
that help me every single day of my life.
الذين ساعدوني كل يوم في حياتي.
And it's important that we all have a support system.
وهذا أمر مهم أن يكون لدينا نظام دعم.
Asking for help is a strength,
طلب المساعدة يدل على القوة،
not a weakness.
ليس الضعف.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
We all need help throughout our lifetime,
نحتاج جميعًا المساعدة على مدار حياتنا،
but it is just as important
لكن من المهم
that we are part of other people's support systems.
أن نكون جزءًا من أنظمة الدعم لغيرنا.
We must adopt that way of giving back.
علينا تبني هذه الطريقة من العطاء.
We all obviously have a role to play in our own successes,
لدينا جميعا دور نقوم به في نجاحاتنا الخاصة،
but think about the role we have to play in other people's successes,
لكن فكروا في الدور الذي نقوم به في نجاحات الآخرين.
just like people do for me every single day.
مثلما يفعل الناس معي كل يوم.
It's vitally important that we help each other,
تشكل مساعدة بعضنا البعض أهمية فعلية،
because society is increasingly placing people in silos
لأن المجتمع سرعان ما يضع الناس في قوالب
based on biases and ideologies.
معتمدا على الانحياز والعقائد.
And we must look past the surface
علينا أن ننظر إلى الواقع
and be confronted with the truth
ونواجه الحقيقة
that none of us are what you can see.
أنّ جوهر كل أحد منا ليس فيما تراه.
There's more to us than that,
يوجد داخلنا ما هو أكثر من ذلك،
and we're all dealing with things that you cannot see.
ونتعامل مع أمور لا تراها.
So living a life free of judgment
عيش الحياة بدون إطلاق الأحكام
allows all of us to share those experiences together
يسمح لنا بمشاركة هذه الخبرات معًا
and have a totally different perspective,
ولدينا وجهة نظر مختلفة كليًا،
just like the couple of people I mentioned earlier in my stories.
مثل الشخصين الذين ذكرتهما أول قصتي.
So remember, the only shoes
لذا تذكروا، الوضع الوحيد
you truly can walk in are your own.
الذي يمكنكم التعامل معه هو وضعكم أنتم.
I cannot walk in yours.
لا أستطيع الحكم على وضعكم.
I know you can't walk in my size 1s --
أعلم أنه لا يمكنكم وضع أنفسكم مكان حجمي الصغير--
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
but you can try.
لكنكم تستطيعون المحاولة.
But we can do something better than that.
لكننا نستطيع فعل ما هو أفضل.
With compassion, courage and understanding,
بالعاطفة والشجاعة والتفهم،
we can walk side by side
نستطيع المضي جنبًا إلى جنب
and support one another,
ودعم بعضنا البعض،
and think about how society can change
والتفكير حول كيفية تغيير المجتمع
if we all do that
إذا فعلنا جميعًا ذلك
instead of judging on only what you can see.
بدلًا من الحكم على الذي ترونه.
Thank you.
شكرًا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)